hard work. Uh it's really too many
people to name, but entire personnel
department, uh our coaching staff, our
operations, player engagement,
everybody. Just really uh want to give
appreciation for all their hard work
that they've done up to this point.
Still a little bit more work to do, but
really appreciate everything. Questions?
>> Brad, I know you know how how serious
you take every draft, but you know, we
was talking to Dan and some of the guys
on their ride and they were saying this
year you skipped out on this meeting to
focus that much more on the draft. So
just talk about, you know, the the how
what do you feel any pressure or
anything to get it right even more or
just to talk about how much more
emphasis you putting on this draft to
even skip out and just be that focused
and that dialed in?
>> Uh well, you know, it was really more so
um in the past where I've gotten for our
process. Um
it's a lot of time that you miss and so
by the time that you get back, you're
kind of in a I'm kind of in kind of a
makeup mode because of all the time that
you miss for our process. So that's why
um I just kind of just said, you know,
look um in order for me to kind of try
to avoid being in that makeup mode
because now you hop into draft meetings
with the scouts and blah blah blah and
it just keeps rolling, but you missed a
good chunk of time for us. And so um
that was that's what went into it. Sure.
>> Uh we haven't really talked to you since
free agency. So, can you just um
obviously didn't add any topline guys?
Not that we expected. You know, the
biggest uh uh cost free agents um but
how do you feel like you addressed your
your needs and you know filled whatever
holes you you thought you had?
>> Yeah, I mean I feel like uh we did the
best we could and we um we maximized the
resources that we had available and
that's that's my job to do that and I
think that we accomplished that.
>> You referred to uh financial
constraints. How how do you imagine that
evolving over the next couple years?
Like when you look at your cap table, do
you do you kind of feel like you'll be
in that place indefinitely? Um or do you
think there's a chance anything changes
over the next couple years in that
regard?
>> I mean, yeah. I mean, it's look, every
single year is different. Um you know,
you just you just don't know. um you
know but yeah there were there were some
there there there are some things that
we are currently navigating through but
I do think that they're good problems um
that we are navigating through and um
you know I would much rather have the
good problems that we have to navigate
through whatever the the the term I use
financial constraints whatever it is but
uh but at the end of the day I I think
they're good problems I'd rather have
those problems in the other way but it
could it it could change I don't know
what next year is going to bring you
know Um but you know, we'll just um but
we'll we'll be prepared and we'll
adjust.
>> Red,
>> it seemed like you had another followup.
>> Well, I was going to say that and you
you also mentioned, you know, the
one-year deals give you a lot of
flexibility. I'm just curious, what are
some other I guess strategies or
mechanisms that you can use as a a GM to
um you know, maintain that flexibility
outside of one-year deals?
>> Uh you mean to just add more of
multi-year deals?
>> No, no. I'm just I'm asking outside of
one-year deal. like how what are some
other strategies that you use to
maintain roster flexibility on a
year-to-year basis?
>> Oh, there's a lot of levers that you
have at your disposal. Uh you just have
to just know when is the right time. You
got to be very strategic. You got to be
smart when to use those levers. But
there's there's multiple things that you
can do from a roster construction
standpoint. Um but you know, but again,
like I say, each year is different. So
there's times where it might make sense
to trade a player. It might make sense
to trade for a player. might, you know,
might help you out from a salary
standpoint. So, every single year is
different. Uh uh but we we have we we do
a lot of hard work on that stuff on the
front end. Make sure we're prepared and
we'll adjust accordingly.
>> Right now that you've done um your full
evaluations. The team sits at number 17.
Do you have 17 first round grades on
some of the pro on the prospects? And
just give me your thoughts on the
overall class and available potentially
in the first round.
>> Yeah. Um we're not there yet uh in terms
of um you know um having a absolute
count in terms of um we still have some
more work to to do um you know in the
this week for sure. Um so we're not
there yet. Um but we feel pretty good.
Um you know I I I think we'll still be
able to be uh able to get a good player.
Um I do think that the this draft is not
too much different than what's been in
the past probably couple years. Um, so,
uh, but I I do feel obviously we're
picking higher than we have been in the
past. So, hopefully that'll put us in
position to get a better player. I've
>> seen some reports in recent weeks that
like national reporters expect it to be
a trade heavy first round. Are you
getting an inclination of that?
>> I have not. Um, it's probably it's a
little so early um that that that
action. You know, usually calls will
start to happen um but um we haven't
gotten to that point yet. Um but it
could be. Brad, the balance uh in the
draft between getting a guy who you
think might be impact immediately or
more long-term, has that balance changed
over the last couple of years as new
challenges have presented for your
roster?
>> No, it's it's it's a fair question. Um,
I always think, you know, because like
I've always said, the reason why we
always go like the best player available
approach is because there is only one
draft and the roster is going to change
every single year. Every single year
it's going to be new needs, going to be,
you know, contracts are going to expire,
things are going to happen. So what may
not seem as immediate I need this right
now for this year that might not be the
case for the next year. So um so that
that's what's that that's what's been
our approach on on that. Um but you know
there there there's times where you
might you know it it lines up like I
said maybe the best player is a
perceived need and it lines up that way.
It's it's lined up like that in the past
but um but that's not always the case.
Ron, you've had you've had some success
drafting some players who are injured
like J Mo. Uh, and obviously you've had
some others have gone the others way
other way like like like Henden. How do
you decide how you're going to take an
injured player?
>> Yeah, it depends on what the injury is.
Uh, it depends on uh, you know, what the
injury history has been in the past. Um,
so you know, like take like JMO, you
know, that was, you know, really his
first major injury. Uh, we felt pretty
good about what the injury was and felt
pretty good about with the with where
medical advancements are at this point.
Um, we felt pretty good about that. The
same same thing with with with Hinden. I
don't I don't think Hinden uh I don't
think his injury was the reason of why
it didn't work out that way. But, um,
but yeah, you just got to look at
everything. Um, you know, it's just you
just got to feel good about it. But it's
case by case for sure.
>> One of the things we're seeing with uh
with NIL is is
>> players staying a little bit longer in
college. I'm just curious when it comes
to age with the draft when you're
evaluating tape of say a 24 25 year old.
Does that have to be a little bit
cleaner tape knowing that you want maybe
instant impact whereas 20 21 year old
you can project a little bit see a
little bit. I'm just curious how you
approach kind of the age element of the
draft that we've seen now holding
players before.
>> Yeah. No. And Tim, I I think it goes
both ways. It just it depends. Um, you
know, you know, what has the tape looked
like? How consistent has a player been
for an older player uh older coming out
in the draft? So, if it's 24, 25 years
old, uh, now, first of all, you got to
have to start adjusting as well because
like you said, these kids are staying in
a much longer time. So, you're going to
get some older prospects. So, um, maybe
some c some c some positions that
maturity helps. you know, some sometimes
it may be a little bit more of a warning
sign. Um, but it is something that we've
had uh adjusted to. Um, but you know,
uh, I think it's it's it's case by case.
Uh, you know, it just depends on the
player, depends on the position. It's a
lot of factors that that go into it.
>> You know, like one of the topics
associated with that is like so many
people speculate about, well, he's going
to be 30 when a second contract rolls
around. Like how much weight do you put
into that?
>> Yeah. No, you you got to be prepared for
that because it's it's real, man. So
like you say like look you guys 24 25
years old now you know and you know he's
going to be looking at 30 you know by
the time a second contract comes okay so
how much longevity it is maybe he hadn't
played a long time and he doesn't have
as much wear and tear but you know
father time is father time too so but
you you have to look at all of it and uh
again it's it's case by case but it it
is real though
>> defensive end what what's your
confidence in in right tackle defensive
end. What What's your confidence level
in Borham and want them if if those
guys, you know, that that they can be
every down starter types or do you have
to, you know, supplement that in the
draft?
>> Yeah, I mean, uh, I' I've said in the
past, um, I think I thought Borne put
out good tape this year. Um, I don't I
don't foresee that. You know, you don't
have a crystal ball, but from what last
thing I saw on tape, you know, I do
think that he's got starter level
ability, and same as Wanom, you know,
you got, you're talking about guys that
have been starters in the NFL. Um, but
just kind of look at where the trend is
going, where the arrow is going. The
last time they're still young. Um, but,
uh, we we feel good about both of them,
so we don't feel like it's, you know,
um, we have to supplement them because
>> out there that, uh, you aren't doing a
local proday this year. Um, just kind of
curious uh, why you made that decision.
Yeah, just internally, you know, we just
kind of made a decision to kind of just
um utilize that that time on for some
other things, but still uh still utilize
the local visits as well. So, we we
still utilize the local visits, but
we're just not we just made the decision
really uh last summer to do away with uh
proday and we'll see how it goes. If we
feel like we missed something um by not
doing it, then we'll look at it and
adjust again.
back real quick.
>> Not to show your hand too much, but how
many offensive tackles do you see in
that first round or even in the second
round as potential first day starters in
this draft?
>> Man, I I I think anytime you're dealing
with anytime you're dealing with a
rookie, I don't care where you draft
them at, you know, you're going to have
to be prepared for a little bit of
growth, period. So, um it's just it's
it's it's hard to say. Um, some some
guys may be a little bit more ready, but
you know, you just never know. So, I
can't really give you really a a good
answer on that one in terms of day one
right now because any anytime you draft
a rookie, I think you're going to have
to be prepared for some development
growth period
this year and um are deeper than others
and within our stuff. Are you getting an
older draft class now overall? Are you
guys staying? Yeah, I mean that's just
been the nature of, you know, whether
it's NIL or, you know, the COVID period
starting to come to a close. Um, you're
just you're you're getting more older
players. Um, but that it it doesn't it
doesn't scare us away from, you know,
not picking a player uh just because
he's a little more advanced in age or
anything. But yeah, that has been a
little bit more prevalent because of
both u kids staying in school longer and
then you know there's still some little
trickle down from CO as well. Still,
>> was it a neat draft or is this a normal
draft compared to other year?
>> I think it's very similar to the past
couple of drafts um you know when the
whole um when the amount of underassmen
that would enter the draft kind of
drastically fell off. So that's why I
would compare it to the past couple of
drafts.
>> Yeah, you open this up every year with
gratitude for your staff.
>> Just want to dig a little deeper there
with with a specific staff member. You
you promoted Brian Hudsmith uh three
years ago. I know you go way back,
covered kind of the same area of the
country for a while. Just curious, um I
guess you speak a lot in superpowers.
You know, what what's Brian's superpower
in his role?
>> Yeah, he just has a lot of experience.
Um he's he's very organized. He's a good
evaluator. Um, you know, I used to be,
like you mentioned, um, being out in the
Southeast with Hudmith and kind of
seeing the way he goes about his work.
Um, you know, as much as scouting is
evolving, uh, you still need to have
some old school roots, you know, and
there's some there there's still some
grassroot level things that you can't
there there's steps you cannot skip
basically in the scouting process. And
that's what I really appreciate about
HUD is HUD's gonna make sure that those
steps aren't aren't getting skipped
because they're critical.
>> Process evolved though from year to
year. Like is it like do you still have
the same level anxiety from the first
year or it just seems like you making
all these different changes? Like how
much has your draft process evolved? Has
it gotten better? Like just going into
this year like kind of your mindset
entering this year's draft?
>> Yeah, we've I think we've evolved a lot.
Um, you know, it's something that we
take a long hard look at, uh, after each
draft to, you know, see things that we
like that we're doing, things that we
could tweak, things that we could do
better, and implement those things and
just see how it goes. But, you know, I
think it's important to, first of all,
you can't be scared to make those
evolutions, but also, you got to look
back at and make sure that they were the
right things. And uh there's sometimes
where you tried something and it you
didn't get the results that you really
wanted and you know you got to tweak
again. So um but uh yeah we we have had
a lot of evolution from the first time.
But the one thing that has not changed
and that has stayed consistent is the
film and you know that's that's first
and foremost. Um that's the reason why
we're acquiring these players is to be
good football players. So that part
really hasn't evolved. Um, and that part
hasn't changed, but we definitely made a
lot of evolutions in other areas.
>> Brad, going back to to Brad's question
about the offensive tackles for a
minute. Yeah,
>> it does seem like as many as seven
offensive tackles have been projected or
or mocked to to go in the first round.
Just what's your evaluation of the top
of the offensive tackle class? And do
you guys feel like that's a long-term
need for you guys? Uh, I mean, I think
anytime you can acquire an offensive
tackle that's a good player. Um, you
know, I always think, you know, if you
look at it like an offensive tackle or,
you know, uh, you know, you call that
premium position category. Um, you know,
I don't think you can ever really have
enough of them. Those guys are hard to
find. Um, but, you know, you got to make
sure that you get the right one. But um
but you know I think there's some
there's some good ones you know uh we'll
just kind of see how it falls.
>> What are the premium positions in your
eyes?
>> What are the premium positions?
>> Well based on what you guys have always
said.
>> No but I mean but you guys tell us what
the premium positions are. Right.
>> Said premium positions his question. So
I don't know if you had your own
definition of premium position.
>> So the positions that we did not draft
in 2023. That's the that's those are the
you know those are the positions right
>> I mean I think most people think pass
rusher quarterback offensive tackle so I
don't know if you align with that your
vision aligns with that so
>> agree
>> at at quarterback I don't know if that's
a premium position how does how does
Terion's situation play into you know
any needs or you know that you may have
or what you may do in the draft
>> um you know um we've put out statements
about that there's no updates
I'm
>> with the draft development and resign
model that you guys have implemented.
How much harder is it now given where
you're drafting because of the success
you've had and also the fact that you've
have fewer picks in the top 100 than say
you did earlier in your tenure.
>> How does it affect things?
>> Yeah. How harder is it to implement that
model uh the draft development reside
when you have fewer picks in that top
100 range? I mean, it it it doesn't
really pose a challenge in terms of the
acquisition of the players. Um, you
know, look, uh, there's there's a lot of
different ways that you can navigate
with having less picks. Um, look, you
might have a lot of picks, you know, and
that might not be the case on drafting
in terms of what you trade, what you
acquire, all that kind of stuff, but um,
but yeah, that's that's kind of what you
want if you can get a good football
player that ends up fitting the vision
that you had. and you know, um, he makes
it to where he's earned a second
contract, you know, that's that's really
what what you want. Um, but you know,
that doesn't that doesn't always affect
it, but it doesn't affect like whether
you have more picks or less picks. Um,
you know, that model that we have used
in the past, uh, I don't I don't see
that changing with the amount of picks
we have. Sorry Brad, that drafting
>> and then as a as a defense is currently
constituted. Uh
>> are are you confident that it's
championship level at this at this stage
>> as a defense is?
>> Yeah, I mean I that's those are our
hopes, you know, that's you know um
look, we're we're never going to be
satisfied uh in terms of where we're at,
you know. Um you know, and that's what
me and Dan are always constantly looking
at, man. We're always constantly looking
at personnel and how to add more and
tweaks and like like all this stuff, you
know, certainly from a schematic
standpoint that's more of a damn
question, but I know that we're looking
at that all the time. So, um so whatever
you're saying like how it looks right
now at this day, then you know that may
not be the case because RAW is looking
to add and you know, evolve it and make
it better all the time.
>> The drafting challenge for you
>> early on drafting challenge
>> drafting challenge for you how it's
evolved over the early on you could take
anybody any position you needed
everything
>> it's gotten more specific and I assume
more difficult as it as it goes on do
you feel at this stage even more
pressure to target what appears to be
specific needs
>> not really um actually I think sometimes
you can get in trouble by doing that
just because you might start to reach
for a certain player because you feel
like you need that position
And you don't never like you never want
to feel that way when you select a
player. You pass up a really good player
that you liked even more, but there is a
a question mark on your roster. So, you
just go ahead and you get that player
that you weren't as excited about. It's
hard to sleep at I know I know for me
it's hard to sleep at night when you do
that when you don't really get the
player that you really really wanted
because you you reach for a need. And if
that reach, you already reached for it.
So you already reached for a player that
you weren't as fired up, but he fit a
certain position. And then what if the
player shows or demonstrates the reason
why you weren't as fired up about him?
So now you've reached for the guy and
now the guy's not even performing up to
standards. The same reason why you had
reservations about him, now you're
really in trouble. So that's why I think
you got to be careful with that.
>> You have done that before, reaching what
you regreted. No,
I not that I can remember.
>> Are you saying that I have
>> Well, no. You said you hate that feeling
when you
>> Oh, yeah. I just know like we we've
never done that, but I can only imagine
like that's a that's a hard like you
can't you can't take a player that you
really don't really you're not fired up
about because he plays a certain
position. And then the reason why you
weren't fired up about him, he shows
that on on the field and that's why you
had reservation for him. And so now it's
you got the double whammy, you know. So
no, we we haven't done that. We only
take players that we're really excited
about. Brad, if organizationally, if
there was a player out there, obviously
not a quarterback, who you thought could
put you over the top, even though
there's no guarantee you'd get to the
Super Bowl, would you, for lack of a
better term, after the picks, go all in,
whatever word you want to use, if you if
you guys felt that there was a guy out
there that would in your mind pretty
close, guarantee you get to the Super
Bowl.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. If it's the
right guy. Yeah. I mean, you guys know
me. I mean, I feel like you guys get mad
at me sometimes. I do that too much
sometimes. But no, I if we we have that
kind of conviction for a player.
Absolutely. We we're going to go and get
them.
>> Just two housekeeping things to fit your
options. Uh have you picked those up on
on those two guys yet or if not, I
assume you will, but will you?
>> We haven't yet, but we've already had
discussions about it. Yep. About about
both of them.
>> And then Ruben Bane, the the story came
out yesterday that he was involved in a
a fatal accident. Um, I don't know if
that was something you knew ahead of
time. Do you have to do more research on
that? What do you think the chances are
that maybe he's available to you at 17
after that that report?
>> Uh, you know, we've we've known that for
a while. Um, so that that doesn't really
change anything uh from our standpoint.
Thanks.
Appreciate